http://www.stmungos.org/privacy-policy

Give
Privacy PolicyWe take your privacy very seriously and will take all necessary care to guard any personal data that we gather.Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession.  The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).Who are we?The Vestry of St Mungo’s Balerno and our Clergy are our data controllers who comply with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.What do we do with personal data?We use your personal data for the following purposes:To administer our church congregation member lists including our address listTo manage our employees and volunteer teamsTo fundraise and promote the interests of the charityTo maintain our own accounts and records (including processing gift aid applications)To inform you of news, events and activities run by St Mungo’s churchTo maintain individual’s attendance at our small groups and total counts for our main servicesTo enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the publicTo share your contact details with the diocesan office if you are appointed to a role within the congregation or diocese for the purposes of church administration;To share your contact details with the General Synod Office if you are appointed to a role within the congregation or diocese for the purposes of church administration;The legal basisExplicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aidProcessing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law.Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: –the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); andthere is no disclosure to a third party without consent.Processing is necessary for our legitimate interests. This means that we can process your personal data if (i) we have a genuine and legitimate reason; and (ii) are not harming any of your rights and interests.Your privacyYour personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties outside of the church with your consent.If you serve on any team or take on any duty, rota or role within the congregation, your personal data may be shared with other members of the congregation. You will be informed if your personal data will be shared more widely.We may also share your information or disclose it to third parties where required to comply with any court order or other legal obligation or when data is requested by government or law enforcement authorities, to enforce any agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, members of the congregation or others.How long do we keep personal data?We keep data in accordance with the guidance provided by the Scottish Episcopal Church.Specifically, we retain Communicant and Adherent Roll data while it is still current and historic records are held in our archive for 6 years; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 7 years after the tax year to which they relate; and church registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently.Your rightsUnless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –The right to request a copy of your personal data which the Clergy/Vestry of St Mungo’s, Balerno holds about you;The right to request that the Clergy/Vestry of St Mungo’s, Balerno corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Clergy/Vestry of St Mungo’s, Balerno to retain such data;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any timeThe right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable).The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable).The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.ChangesThe church may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to ensure compliance with changes or amendments to the law of the UK. Any amended version will be available on our website. We suggest that you visit our website regularly to keep up to date with any changes.Contact usTo exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints please in the first instance contact us at enquiries@stmungos.org.You can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
